# Erica J. Kim

408-335-5962 - <u>e.kim@berkeley.edu</u> firefly454.github.io - linkedin.com/in/erica-kim-3372004a

# **SUMMARY**

Recent PhD Graduate of the University of California, Berkeley's Biophysics program, with 8+ years of experience of designing experiments and analyzing results in advanced research settings. Versatile, creative, and efficient, with proven analytical and communication skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Udacity Data Analyst Nanodegree**

Expected completion date: May 2016

# PhD in Biophysics, University of California, Berkeley

December 2014

• GPA: 3.8/4.0

• Awarded National Science Foundation (NSF) Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship (2 years full tuition + living stipend)

#### BA in Mathematics, New York University

May 2008

• GPA: 3.8/4.0; minor: Computer Science

• Awarded Presidential Honors Scholarship (4 years full tuition)

# **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Scipy, ggplot, R, C++, Latex, Matlab

Databases and Software: MongoDB, MySQL, Git, Microsoft Excel, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

### **SELECTED PROJECTS** (visit <u>firefly454.github.io</u> for more information)

- Exploratory Analysis of Historical Loan Data from Prosper lending marketplace. R
- Predicting Persons-of-Interest in the Enron Email Dataset, using Machine Learning. *Python*

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Data Science Workshop Participant, University of California, Berkeley

**July 2015** 

- Developed an accurate **prediction model for San Francisco crime classification**, using data from SF Open Data, as part of an ongoing Kaggle competition
- Placed in **top 7% in rankings** (based on log-loss error) at time of code submission

# **Graduate Research Assistant, University of California, Berkeley**

Sept 2009 - Dec 2014

- Investigated the biomechanics of hummingbird flight, in order to elucidate the physiological limits to different flight modes
- Analyzed data (consisting of high-speed video files) by writing code to efficiently perform 3D-image analysis and aerodynamic modeling, in Matlab
- Extensively used R to carry out statistical analyses and generate publication-quality images
- Formally mentored 3 undergraduates in the Undergraduate Research Apprentice Program (URAP)

# Graduate Student Instructor, University of California, Berkeley

Sept 2012 - Dec 2012

• Led laboratory section of Integrative Biology Motor Control course, guiding ~20 students through real and computer-simulated experiments as well as holding tutoring sessions

# Assistant Researcher, Applied Math Lab, New York University

Jun 2005 - Aug 2008

- Designed, implemented, and analyzed experiments on the biomechanics of swimming *C. elegans*, including photolithography fabrication
- Trained 4 graduate students from theoretical backgrounds in experimental methods of complex fluids

# **Teaching Assistant, New York University**

Sept 2006 - Dec 2006

- Initiated change in physics department to be the 1st undergraduate teaching assistant for General Physics course
- Led weekly discussion session for ~20 students; held 2-hour weekly 1-on-1 office hours